[
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 1,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION E: African Prose</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>AMMA DARKO: Faceless</strong></p><p> </p><p>Comment on the role of Fofo in the novel.</p>",
        "answer": "<p>Candidates are expected to mention the following points among others:</p><p>i. Fofo as the central character.</p><p>ii. Fofo as a window to the predicaments of the street children.</p><p>iii. Fofo’s encounter with Kabria as a turning point in the development of the plot.</p><p>iv. Fofo’s role in exposing parental irresponsibility.</p><p>v. The unravelling of Baby T’s murder through Fofo’s encounter with Kabria.</p><p>vi. Fofo as symbol of bright future for the street child.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 2,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION E: African Prose</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>AMMA DARKO: Faceless</strong></p><p> </p><p>Discuss parental negligence in the novel.</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The following points are expected from the candidates:</p><p>i. Definition of parental negligence.</p><p>ii. Maa Tsuru’s father’s refusal to accept responsibility for her mother and herself.</p><p>iii. Parents reversing the role with children, as in the case of Maa Tsuru.</p><p>iv. Male parents neglecting care for children.</p><p>v. Parents failing to correct and keep children on track as seen in Odarley’s mother.</p><p>vi. Parents bullying children as seen in Poison’s step-father.</p><p>vii. Parents exploiting children for financial gain.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 3,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION E - African Prose</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>BAYO ADEBOWALE: Lonely Days</strong></p><p> </p><p>How do the men of Kufi behave towards their women?</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The following points should be well developed by the candidates:</p><p>i. Men are the overlords in Kufi and women know and have come to terms with this fact.</p><p>ii. Women must not rise above their status.</p><p>iii. Women must be timid and self-effacing.</p><p>iv. Yaremi rejects the system, to the annoyance of the men.</p><p>v. Wife-beating as a means of keeping women in their place.</p><p>vi. Polygamy as a means of keeping women in check.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 4,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION E - African Prose</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>BAYO ADEBOWALE: Lonely Days</strong></p><p> </p><p>Discuss Yaremi’s marriage in the novel.</p>",
        "answer": "<p>The required answers should include:</p><p>i. The account of Yaremi’s marriage being her recollections as her husband has died before the events of the novel.</p><p>ii. Yaremi’s marriage being successful and normal.</p><p>iii. Yaremi’s marriage being blessed with three children.</p><p>iv. Yaremi’s love for Ajumobi expressed when he is alive and after his death.</p><p>v. Yaremi’s refusal to marry any other man after Ajumobi’s death.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 5,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION F: NON - AFRICAN PROSE</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>NATIVE SON - RICHARD WRIGHT</strong></p><p> </p><p>What is Bigger’s attitude towards religion?</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The following points are expected from the candidates:</p><p>i. Bigger’s family and background.</p><p>ii. His notion of inequality of races which religion does not correct.</p><p>iii. His mother and Rev. Hammond’s attempt to instil in him their religion and his rejection.</p><p>iv. The Ku Klux Klan’s wrong use of the cross to instil fear in the Negro.</p><p>v. The notion of happiness after death.</p><p>vi. His view of religion as a tool of sustaining white supremacy.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 6,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION F: NON - AFRICAN PROSE</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>RICHARD WRIGHT: Native Son</strong></p><p> </p><p>How are the Daltons portrayed in the novel?</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>Candidates are expected to mention the following points:</p><p>i. The Daltons are a wealthy white family.</p><p>ii. Their relationship with blacks and their philanthropy.</p><p>iii. Their capitalist aversion to communism.</p><p>iv. Their blindness to their exploitation of black.</p><p>v. Mary’s obstinacy.</p><p>vi. The Daltons as victims who suffer the effects of reaction.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 7,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION F: NON-AFRICAN PROSE</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>HORACE WALPOLE: The Castle of Otranto</strong></p><p> </p><p>Comment on the evil that befalls Prince Manfred.</p><p></p>",
        "answer": "<p>Candidates are expected to mention the following points among others:</p><p>i. The identity of Prince Manfred.</p><p>ii. Manfred’s ambition to keep the throne in his family.</p><p>iii. The death of Conrad.</p><p>iv. Manfred’s decision to marry Isabella, and its consequences.</p><p>v. Manfred’s ill treatment of his wife, Hippolita, and its consequences on his fortunes.</p><ul>\n<li>Manfred’s killing of Matilda, his daughter.</li>\n<li>Manfred losing the throne.</li>\n</ul>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 8,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION F: NON-AFRICAN PROSE</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>HORACE WALPOLE: The Castle of Otranto</strong></p><p> </p><p>Examine the role of Theodore in the novel.</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The following points are expected from the candidates:</p><p>i. His introduction as a peasant at the beginning of the novel.</p><p>ii. His identification of the helmet that kills Conrad as same as that on Alfonso’s statue..</p><p>iii. His role as an antagonist to Manfred.</p><p>iv. His appearance in the image of Alfonso.</p><p>v. His kindness and warm-heartedness.</p><p>vi. Theodore’s true identity and final taking over as Prince and marrying Isabella.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 9,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION A: African Drama</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>DELE CHARLEY: The Blood of a Stranger</strong></p><p> </p><p>Assess King Santigi V as an unwise ruler.</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The required answers should include:</p><p>i. Santigi totters under the weight of Maligu’s influence.</p><p>ii. He ignores Kindo’s advice and approves the reception of a stranger.</p><p>iii. He does not insist on seeing Maligu’s letter.</p><p>iv. He forges a dangerous relationship with Whitehead.</p><p>v. He banishes Kindo.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 10,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION A: African Drama</strong></p><p><br>\n<strong>DELE CHARLEY: The Blood of a </strong><strong>Stranger</strong></p><p> </p><p>Examine the theme of deceit and intrigue in the drama.<br>\n<br>\n</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The required answers should include:</p><p>i. The play’s concern with the encounter between Mando land and Whitehead.</p><p>ii. Deceit and intrigue as the essential thematic focus of the play.</p><p>iii. Maligu, Soko, Kindo and Whitehead’s engagement in a game to outsmart each other.</p><p>iv. Parker killing Soko; Kindo killing Parker and Whitehead; Kindo being banished.</p><p>v. Deceit and intrigue helping to enhance the plot.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 11,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>Section A: AFRICAN DRAMA</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>FRANK OGODO OGBECHE - Harvest of Corruption</strong></p><p> </p><p>To what extent can Aloho’s tragedy be blamed on the society?</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>Candidates are expected to discuss the following points:</p><p>i. Aloho’s failure to secure a job and how frustration drives her into the path of Ochuole.</p><p>ii. Aloho’s own contribution to her tragedy.</p><p>iii. The significance of the network of corruption: the role of Chief Ade-Amaka, DCOP, Odili, Madam Hoha, etc.</p><p>iv. Aloho’s innocence and naivety and her exploitation by Ochuole in getting her employed in the first place.</p><p>v. The very nature of society; what it takes to succeed or to belong.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 12,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>Section A: AFRICAN DRAMA</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>FRANK OGODO OGBECHE - Harvest of Corruption</strong></p><p> </p><p>Why does Ogeyi dislike Ochuole?</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The required answers should include:</p><p>i. Ogeyi and Ochuole do not meet on stage until Ochuole’s trial.</p><p>ii. Ochuole’s past record counts against her.</p><p>iii. Born-again Ogeyi holds Ochuole’s present waywardness against her.</p><p>iv. Ogeyi does not trust Ochuole.</p><p>v. Ogeyi blames Ochuole and Chief Ade-Amaka for Aloho’s sad end and seeks justice.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 13,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>Section B: NON AFRICAN DRAMA</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>LORRAINE HANSBERRY - A Raisin In The Sun</strong></p><p> </p><p>Compare the characters of Mama and Beneatha in the play.</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>Candidates are expected to discuss the following points:</p><p>i. Mama and Beneatha as mother and daughter.</p><p>ii. Mama as matriarch of the house; Beneatha still in college.</p><p>iii. Mama’s loving nature though firm; Beneatha youthful and fun-loving.</p><p>iv. Mama being representative of the older generation, Beneatha the younger generation.</p><p>v. Mama tolerant and accommodating; Beneatha inconsiderate and intolerant.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 14,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>Section B: NON AFRICAN DRAMA</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>LORRAINE HANSBERRY - A Raisin In The Sun</strong></p><p> </p><p>Comment on Beneatha’s relationship with Joseph Asagai and George Murchison.</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>Candidates should include these in their answers:</p><p>i. Both Joseph Asagai and George Murchison are Beneatha’s boyfriends; Beneatha apparently prefers Joseph.</p><p>ii. Joseph and Beneatha have a lot in common.</p><p>iii. Joseph supports Beneatha.</p><p>iv. George and Beneatha differ in temperament and their preferences; they belong to separate social levels.</p><p>v. George is condescending and unattractive to Beneatha.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 15,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>Section B: NON - AFRICAN DRAMA</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>OLIVER GOLDSMITH - SHE STOOPS TO CONQUER</strong></p><p> </p><p>Consider the attitude of Mr. and Mrs. Hardcastle towards Tony Lumpkin.</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The required answers should include:</p><p>i. The relationship between husband and wife and their treatment of their step-son and son.</p><p>ii. The attitude of Mr. Hardcastle towards Tony.</p><p>iii. The attitude of Mrs. Hardcastle towards Tony.</p><p>iv. Tony’s contribution towards his treatment by both Mr. and Mrs. Hardcastle.</p><p>v. The couple’s individual regard for Tony as he is.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 16,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>Section B: NON - AFRICAN DRAMA</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>OLIVER GOLDSMITH - SHE STOOPS TO CONQUER</strong></p><p> </p><p>Discuss the role of Tony Lumpkin in connection with any three mistakes in the play.</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>Candidates are expected to discuss the following points:</p><p>i. Tony full of tricks.</p><p>ii. Tony misleading the guests.</p><p>iii. Tony and Constance pretending to be in love.</p><p>iv. Tony contriving to retrieve Constance’s jewels from his mother’s custody.</p><p>v. Tony driving his mother round about the house.</p><p>vi. Tony the originator of mistakes.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 17,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION C: AFRICAN POETRY</strong></p><p> </p><p>Examine the tone and mood of the poem, “Ambush”.</p>",
        "answer": "<p>The following points are expected from the candidates:</p><p>i. The theme of the poem.</p><p>ii. The use of declarative sentences which convey both tone and mood.</p><p>iii. The non-defining clauses which present the activities of the fearsome predatory forces.</p><p>iv. The resultant joyless effect of the tone and mood.</p><p>v. The cumulative effect of the sentences in foregrounding the theme and morbid tone and mood.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 18,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p>Explain the poet’s attitude to African traditional culture in “Vanity”.</p>",
        "answer": "<p>The required answers should include:</p><p>i. The positive view of traditional culture represented by the ancestors.</p><p>ii. The alienation that has ensued through the wilful neglect of ancestral guidance.</p><p>iii. The consequences of the wilful neglect.</p><p>iv. The placing of blame on the people themselves for their situation.</p><p>v. The people’s ineffective cry for sympathy.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 19,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION D: NON-AFRICAN POETRY</strong></p><p> </p><p>How does the boy justify his reluctance to go to school?</p><p> </p>",
        "answer": "<p>The following are expected from the candidates:</p><p>i. A brief discussion of the theme.</p><p>ii. The boy’s attachment to nature.</p><p>iii. The boy’s description of the atmosphere of school on a “summer morn”.</p><p>iv. The boy’s appeal to “father and mother” to agree with him.</p><p>v. The argument for a change of a sort.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 20,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p>Examine three features of metaphysical poetry in “The Pulley”.</p><p> </p>",
        "answer": "<p>The required answer should include the following points:</p><p>i. God’s relationship with man explicated metaphysically.</p><p>ii. Extended metaphor.</p><p>iii. Conceit.</p><p>iv. Wit.</p><p>v. Dramatic presentation.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 21,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION E: African Prose</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>AMMA DARKO: Faceless</strong></p><p> </p><p>Discuss the significance of Agbogbloshie Market in the novel.</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The required answers should include:</p><p>i. Background of Agbogbloshie Market.</p><p>ii. Deprivation as a root cause for forcing people especially children out of their homes.</p><p>iii. Deprivation of basic amenities within the market itself.</p><p>iv. Misery the characters are put through by exploitation, suffering, hunger, poverty and bullying.</p><p>v. The decadence of the characters mentally, morally and physically.</p><p>vi. Unchecked lawlessness even in the presence of law enforcement officers.</p><p>vii. A business centre for traders and buyers of all kinds. Particularly, it is the place where Kabria encounters Fofo, which leads to Fofo’s rehabilitation and the resolution of mystery surrounding Baby T’s death.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 22,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION A: African Drama</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>DELE CHARLEY: The Blood of a Stranger</strong></p><p> </p><p>Examine the role of the shrine in the culture of Mando Land.</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The required answers should include:</p><p>i. The statement of the central theme.</p><p>ii. The location of the shrine.</p><p>iii. The role of the shrine.</p><p>iv. The desecration of the shrine.</p><p>v. The consequences of the desecration.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 23,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>SECTION A: African Drama</strong></p><p><br>\n<strong>DELE CHARLEY: The Blood of a </strong><strong>Stranger</strong></p><p> </p><p>How does the relationship between Santigi and Kindo affect the future of Mando land?</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The required answers should include:</p><p>i. The statement of the central theme.</p><p>ii. The once cordial father-son relationship which became one of discord after the arrival of Whitehead.</p><p>iii. Events leading to the planting of seeds of separation/discord.</p><p>iv. The banishment of Kindo by Santigi supposedly to protect custom.</p><p>v. Implications of the rift between father and son for the future of Mando land.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 24,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p>Examine the poet’s use of sight and sound images in Frost’s Birches.</p><p> </p><p></p>",
        "answer": "<p>The required answer should include the following points:</p><p>i. Statement of the theme.</p><p>ii. Description of the birches.</p><p>iii. Use of sight and sound images.</p><p>iv. Use as pastime (leisure).</p><p>v. Impact on persona’s experience of and outlook on life. Words and phrases appealing to the senses of sight and sound.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 25,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p>Discuss the defects of a summer’s day as highlighted by the poet in Shall I Compare Thee to a Summer’s Day?</p><p> </p><p></p>",
        "answer": "<p>Candidates are expected to discuss the following points:</p><p>i. Statement of the theme of a lover’s beauty as eternal and immortal.</p><p>ii. Summer’s inherent qualities.</p><p>iii. Defects of summer in comparison.</p><p>iv. Juxtaposition of a summer’s day and the lover’s beauty.</p><p>v. Consequences of a summer’s day’s defects.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 26,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p>Examine the persona’s resolve to be a revolutionary in<em> The Dining Table</em>.</p>",
        "answer": "<p>Candidates are expected to discuss the following points:</p><p>i. Statement of the theme.</p><p>ii. The traumatic experience of a family at the table.</p><p>iii. Hunger in the post-war society.</p><p>iv. All round insecurity and danger.</p><p>v. The cumulative effect.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 27,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p>Comment on the poet’s use of rhetorical question in Vanity.</p>",
        "answer": "<p>Candidates are expected to discuss the following points:</p><p>i. Statement of the theme<em>.</em></p><p>ii. Definition of “rhetorical question” as the question asked.</p><p>iii. Appeal to the senses.</p><p>iv. Appeal to emotion.</p><p>v. General effects of the various appeals.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 28,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>Section B: NON - AFRICAN DRAMA</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>OLIVER GOLDSMITH - SHE STOOPS TO CONQUER</strong></p><p> </p><p>Discuss the information provided by Act 1, Scene 1 and how it advances the plot of the play.</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The required answers should include:</p><p>i. Statement of the central theme of love and marriage in a middle/upper-class society.</p><p>ii. Introduction of characters and their relationship.</p><p>iii. Information on the characters.</p><p>iv. Implication on the advancement of the plot.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 29,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>Section B: NON - AFRICAN DRAMA</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>OLIVER GOLDSMITH - SHE STOOPS TO CONQUER</strong></p><p> </p><p>Discuss the view that Tony is to blame for the failure of Hastings’ plan to elope with Constance.</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The required answers should include:</p><p>i. Statement of the central theme of love and marriage in a middle/upper-class society.</p><p>ii. Character identification.</p><p>iii. The plan to elope.</p><p>iv. The attempt to elope.</p><p>v. Tony’s remedy.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 30,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>Section B: NON AFRICAN DRAMA</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>LORRAINE HANSBERRY - A Raisin In The Sun</strong></p><p> </p><p>Consider the relationship between Mama and Travis.</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The following points are expected from the candidates:</p><p>i. Statement of the central theme of the play.</p><p>ii. Character identification.</p><p>iii. Mama’s deep love for Travis and concern about his well being.</p><p>iv. Travis’ reciprocal love for and trust in Mama.</p><p>v. Mama’s wishes for a better life for Travis.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 31,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>Section B: NON AFRICAN DRAMA</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>LORRAINE HANSBERRY - A Raisin In The Sun</strong></p><p> </p><p>Comment on the character and role of Asagai in the play.</p><ol>\n</ol><p> </p>",
        "answer": "<p>Candidates’ response should include:</p><p>i. Statement of the central theme of the play.</p><p>ii. Character identification.</p><p>iii. Asagai’s intelligence and charm.</p><p>iv. Asagai’s role in the play.</p><p>v. His pride in his African heritage and instrument through which Beneatha and her family become aware of their African heritage.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 32,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>Section A: AFRICAN DRAMA</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>FRANK OGODO OGBECHE - Harvest of Corruption</strong></p><p> </p><p>How is ACP Yakubu presented in the play?</p><ol>\n</ol>",
        "answer": "<p>The following points are expected from the candidates:</p><p>i. Statement of the central theme.</p><p>ii. Physical attributes and conduct.</p><p>iii. Commitment to work.</p><p>iv. Believer in teamwork.</p><p>v. Eventual success in prosecuting crime.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 33,
        "year": 2019,
        "question": "<p><strong>Section A: AFRICAN DRAMA</strong></p><p> </p><p><strong>FRANK OGODO OGBECHE - Harvest of Corruption</strong></p><p> </p><p>Consider any three dramatic elements used to develop the plot.</p><ol>\n</ol><p> </p>",
        "answer": "<p>The following points are expected from the candidates:</p><p>i. Statement of the central theme.</p><p>ii. The use of allusion, relevance to the plot and examples.</p><p>iii. Use of soliloquy, relevance to the plot and examples.</p><p>iv. Use of symbolism, relevance to the plot and examples.</p><p>v. Use of irony, relevance to the plot and examples.</p><p>vi. Foreshadowing, its relevance to the plot and instances.</p>",
        "type": "theory"
    }
]